Pavel Mineev

Software Engineer

pavel.mineev.me / pavel@mineev.me / linkedin.com/in/akellbl4 / github.com/akellbl4

I have large hands-on experience efficiently coding web apps. I mostly work with the frontend. I've taken part in the development process of small startups as well as large high-load projects.

Experience

Principal Software Engineer, June Homes

April 2020 - Present time

Rental startup based in New York

- Created processes for project lifecycle from development to releases. Utilized code quality and CI/CD tools.
- Architectured and implemented the whole web app with Next.js. It helps the company to scale 10 times
- The web app became ~10x faster in terms of loading speed and performance
- Users spend 3x more time using the application
- Started and scaled frontend team to 6 developers

Principal Software Engineer, Rocketbank

March 2017 - August 2020

A pioneer of mobile banking in Russia

- Started to work as the first frontend developer in the company and then I built up and grew the whole frontend team
- Led development of company's website, online banking web app, accountant web app for businesses, bot for social networks, and marketing projects from scratch to the release
- The release of the new website increased conversion up to x1.5
- Made easy and fast registration form for new customers which decreased time for application by 20%, and increased conversion by 15%

Lead Software Engineer, Mail.ru

August 2015 — December 2016

Top 3 biggest internet companies in Russia and the largest email service in Eastern Europe.

- Implemented cross-portal auth frontend module which could keep multiple parallel sessions that helps more than 10 teams easily implement SSO in their projects
- Architected and implemented the new version of the home page of the portal. It provided new features and encreased users interest and dropped bounce rate 10%

Senior Software Engineer, Mail.ru

October 2013 – August 2015

- Joined the company as a developer in portal team and worked on the home page of the portal and cross-portal components
- Developed frontend and backend (V8) of the high-load project where the main priorities were fault tolerance and performance
- Worked with products managers and designers on improving UX
- Implemented new commercial features that helped to increase the revenue of the project by 12%

Software Engineer, Rambler&Co

August 2012 - June 2013

Top 3 internet portal and search engine in Russia.

- Joined portal team and worked on several projects
- Developed intranet portal from scratch and learned Angular
- Worked on UI/UX of airplane tickets system and increased conversion by 14%

Software Engineer, Mamba.ru

May 2011 - December 2012

The biggest dating site in Eastern Europe that days.

- First serious experience in a big company
- Worked on UI with a multi-language support
- Developed niche projects
- Implemented standardized branding system that helped to run ads from partners 50% faster

Skills

JavaScript

TypeScript

HTML + CSS

React

Next.js

Node.js

Jest, Testing Library

Docker

CI/CD

GoLang

React Native

Gatsby

Redis

MongoDB

Education

Moscow State College of Technology and Management

Computer Science – Computer Software and Automated Systems

2006 - 2010